Dirk Hornung, Ph.D.



PERSONAL

Address:

Carrer Sant Pacia 3, 08001 Barcelona

Phone:

+34 (0)695 460 404

Email:

dirkhornung91@gmail.com

Date of birth:

05.10.1991

Place of birth:

Fulda, Germany

LANGUAGES

German – native

English - proficient

Spanish – proficient

French - intermediate

SKILLS

JavaScript, ES6, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Angular, Webpack, Babel, Git, Jenkins, NPM, Yarn, Jira, GraphQL, Prisma, Node, Express, REST API, AWS, Trello, Gitlab, C++, Java, Typescript, Python, SQL, CSS, HTML, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

OBJECTIVE

Recently graduated theoretical physics PhD candidate with 5+ years of experience in programming JavaScript-based web applications and optimized C++ optimized numerics. Entrepreneurial spirit seeking to apply his Full Stack abilities to the position of JavaScript senior/ Java developer at OIZ.

WORK EXPERIENCE

05/2018 - 01/2019

CTO, CYSAE SEVERLA S.L., Madrid Spain Responsibilities:

- Created an utility token for Cuatre Casas (React, Express Rest API, Ethereum, Solidity, ERC-20)
- Created an on chain document certifier (React, Redux, Redux-Saga, AWS S3, GraphQL, Prisma, Stampery API, Docker, AWS ECS)
- Decentralized votings in companys (React, Redux, Ant Design, Solidity, AWS S3, AWS amplify)

10/2017 - 04/2018

CTO, Aldabot S.L, Barcelona Spain Responsibilities:

- Created a Fintech Chatbot for Messenger (Serverless, AWS Lambda, Facebook API, Dialogflow API Saltedge API, MongoDB)
- Created PWA for the Chatbot (React, Redux, Redux-Saga, AWS amplify)
- Implemented the Chatbot in Liferay (Java, Tomcat, Liferay)

09/2016 - 09/2017

CTO, WeGoLoco, Barcelona Spain Responsibilities:

 Created an Ecommerce App (React Native, Redux, AWS RDS)

02/2016 - 08/2016

CTO, FuldaCity, Fulda Germany Responsibilities:

 Created an Event App (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node, Cordova)

EDUCATION

2015 - 2019

Ph.D., Theoretical Physics, Autonomous University of Barcelona

Thesis: The QCD Strong Coupling from Hadronic Tau Decays,

Created a C++ fitting routine from scratch to extract parameters from CERN data

2014 - 2015

M.Sc., Particle Physics, Autonomous University of Barcelona

Thesis: 1-Loop Anomalous Dimensions of 4-Quark Operators

2011 - 2014

B.Sc., Condensed Matter Physics, Goethe University Frankfurt

Thesis: Band Structure Studies of Graphene and Modified Graphene Structure